Hello welcome to Real easyy English from BBC Learning English I'm Georgie and I'm Neil and in this podcast we have real conversations in
easyenglish to help you improve your English Remember you can read what we're saying on our website BBClearningenglish.com.
How are you today, Georgie, I'm pretty good, Neil.
Thank you.
I'm happy that it's Friday.
me too.
So today we are talking about holidays and our dream destinations.
Great, I love this topic, but can you explain what you mean by destination.
Neil, a destination is what we call a place.
We are going to the place we would like to go to.
Okay, so if we are on a train to visit London, London is our destination, but we often use it when we're talking about holidays or special journeys that 's right.
A dream destination is somewhere we would really like to go and travel on our holiday Okay,
so where is your dream holiday destination Neil?
I like two different kinds of holidays.
I like interesting cities, interesting old cities like European cities, but I also like mountains and countryside.
And those kind of places like in South America, yes, I also have two different types of holidays that I like.
If I want to relax, I usually want to be in the sun by the beach, but I also love to see new and interesting places,
places that you can't see in your own country.
Neil, where's your favorite place you've ever been to Oh well I am I really,
really liked Japan when I visited Japan Okay, so if I go to Japan, what should I do there?
You should eat as much food as you can because the food is fantastic and you can eat in a little noodle shop or you can eat in a big
posh restaurant and it's all amazing.
That sounds so good and I love food Okay, so you said I should try some Japanese restaurants what is this word should,
what does it mean It means I think it's a good idea.
For you to do that that's my advice to you Okay, so it's kind of like a recommendation in this case,
Yeah so when you go to Japan, you should eat sushi, when you go to Japan, you should.
Visit Kyoto to see Zen Gardens.
So how about you, Georgie, what's, what's the best place you've ever been on holiday I.
Really love Edinburgh in Scotland, I love it because it's very green, the city is very close to nature and is'very beautiful,
the buildings are really beautiful.
Okay, so Edinburgh, Georgie, what could I do in Edinburgh Well, in August, for example,
you could go to the fringe Festival, which is a comedy and arts festival.
So you could see some shows or you could go for a walk in the national parks outside of the city or you could go to see some of the museums they have.
There's lots of things you could do Yeah, and when we use could, we're talking about things that are possible.
Yes, and that's different from should because when I say you should do something, it means that it's a good idea or I'm giving you advice,
but could I'm just giving you some options, things that are possible for you to do now we don't.
Always go to another country on holiday or even a different city do we No, now it's actually quite popular to go on holiday inside your own country and we have
a word for this, don't we Neil?
Yes, we do.
and it combines two words, the word stay and the word vacation, put them together, and you have staycation,
and a staycation is a holiday at actually in your house or near your house.
Have you ever done a staycation Neil Yes, plenty of times often on a staycation you might do day trips so you go and visit places in
the area but come home in the evening.
Now the problem with holidays is they are expensive,
we probably need to save up money if we want to travel to all these places apart from the stacation.
Yes, we should save up some money exactly Let's recap the language we learned during the conversation We learned destination,
which we used to talk about a place we are going to.
Or we would like to go to could which we use to talk about something that is possible should,
which we use to talk about something that it's a good idea to do this is advice.
And staycation which is a fun word to talk about a holiday at or near home That's it this real
easy English visit our website.
For more activities and courses to help you with your Englishlearninglish.
com Next time we'll be talking about work and jobs See you bye.